<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2016 Dan Leinir Turthra Jensen <admin@leinir.dk> -->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.peruse.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <developer id="kde.org">
    <name translate="no">KDE</name>
  </developer>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.kde.peruse.desktop</launchable>
  <name>Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="pa">ਪੇਰੁਸ</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxPerusexx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">Peruse</name>
  <summary>Comic Book Reader</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Lector de llibres de còmic</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Lector de llibres de còmic</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Čtečka komiksů</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Anzeigeprogramm für Comic-Book</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Comic Book Reader</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Legilo por komiksoj</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Lector de cómics</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Koomiksite lugemine</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Sarjakuvakatselin</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Lecteur de bandes dessinées</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Lector de libros de banda deseñada</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Pembaca Buku Komik</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Lettore di fumetti</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ka">კომიქსების წიგნების წამკითხავი</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">만화책 뷰어</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Stripboekreader</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pa">ਕਾਮਿਕਸ ਬੁੱਕ ਰੀਡਰ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Czytnik komiksów</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Leitor de Bandas Desenhadas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Čítačka komiksoc</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Bralnik stripov</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Serietidningsläsare</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Çizgi Roman Okuyucusu</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Програма для читання коміксів</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxComic Book Readerxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">漫畫書閱讀器</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      There are many ways to read comic books, and one of those that has become more
      common in recent years is on a computer. Peruse was created as a way to make
      exactly that as easy and pleasant as possible, and to simply get out of the
      way and let you read your comic books. One could say that it allows you to
      peruse your comic books at your leisure, but that would be a silly way of
      putting it - so, peruse your comic books at your leisure!
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Hi ha moltes maneres de llegir còmics, i una de les que ha esdevingut més normal en anys recents és en un ordinador. El Peruse es va crear com una manera de fer-ho exactament tan fàcil i agradable com fos possible, i per a senzillament oblidar-se de la manera i permetre llegir els llibres de còmic. Es podria dir que permet llegir atentament els llibres de còmic en el temps de lleure, però això seria una manera forassenyada de dir-ho, així que llegiu atentament els llibres de còmic en el vostre temps de lleure!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Hi ha moltes maneres de llegir còmics, i una de les que ha esdevingut més normal en anys recents és en un ordinador. Peruse es va crear com una manera de fer-ho exactament tan fàcil i agradable com fora possible, i per a senzillament oblidar-se de la manera i permetre llegir els llibres de còmic. Es podria dir que permet llegir atentament els llibres de còmic en el temps de lleure, però açò seria una manera forassenyada de dir-ho, així que llegiu atentament els llibres de còmic en el vostre temps de lleure!</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">There are many ways to read comic books, and one of those that has become more common in recent years is on a computer. Peruse was created as a way to make exactly that as easy and pleasant as possible, and to simply get out of the way and let you read your comic books. One could say that it allows you to peruse your comic books at your leisure, but that would be a silly way of putting it - so, peruse your comic books at your leisure!</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Estas multaj manieroj legi komiksojn, kaj unu el tiuj, kiuj fariĝis pli oftaj en la lastaj jaroj, estas per komputilo. Peruse estis kreita kiel maniero fari ĝuste tion kiel eble plej facila kaj agrabla, kaj simple foriri kaj lasi vin legi viajn komiksojn. Oni povus diri, ke ĝi permesas tralegi viajn komiksojn laŭplaĉe, sed tio estus stulta maniero diri - do, tralegi viajn komiksojn laŭplaĉe!</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Hay muchas maneras de leer cómics, y una de las que se ha convertido en más común en los últimos años, es la computadora. Peruse fue creado para hacer esto de la manera más fácil y placentera posible, simplemente para no interponerse en su camino y dejarle leer cómics. Alguien podría decir que le permite leer detenidamente sus cómics a su ritmo, pero esto sería una manera un tanto tonta de ponerlo, así que, ¡Lea sus cómics a su ritmo!</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Koomikseid saab mitut moodi lugeda, viimastel aastatel on aga aina levinud komme lugeda neid arvutis. Peruse on loodud just nimelt sihiga muuta see võimalikult lihtsaks ja mugavaks, nii et lugeja saaks keskenduda just koomiksile, mitte rakendusele. Igal juhul - head koomiksite nautimist!</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Sarjakuvakirjoja voi lukea eri tavoin, ja yksi viime aikoina yleisimmistä tavoista on tietokone. Peruse luotiin tekemään siitä mahdollisimman helppoa ja miellyttävää. Se yrittää pysyä poissa tieltä ja antaa sinun vain lukea. Voisi sanoa, että se tekee sarjakuvakirjojen lukemisesta viihdyttävää, mutta se olisi hassusti sanottu – kaikkihan sarjakuvakirjoja lukevat viihtyäkseen!</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Il y a de nombreuses manière de lire des bandes dessinées. L'une d'entre elles est devenue plus commune ces dernières années avec un ordinateur. Peruse a été créé de façon de le faire aussi facilement et agréablement que possible, de le faire aussi un peu différemment et vous laissez lire vos bandes dessinées. Certains diront que cela vous permet de parcourir vos bandes dessinées en toute détente. Mais, cela serait une façon un peu stupide de le résumer ainsi. Aussi, profitez de vos bandes dessinées en toute détente.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Hai moitos xeitos de ler libros de banda deseñada, e un dos máis comúns nos últimos anos é usar un computador. Peruse creouse para facer iso o máis fácil e agradábel posíbel, e para non estar no medio e deixarlle ler os seus libros de banda deseñada.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Ada banyak cara untuk membaca buku komik, dan salahsatu yang menjadi lebih umum dalam beberapa tahun terakhir adalah di komputer. Membaca dengan teliti diciptakan sebagai cara untuk membuat hal itu semudah dan semenyenangkan mungkin, dan hanya untuk keluar dari jalan dan membiarkan kamu membaca buku komikmu. Orang bisa mengatakan bahwa itu memungkinkan kamu membaca buku komikmu di waktu luangmu, tetapi itu akan menjadi cara yang konyol untuk menggambarkannya - jadi, bacalah buku komik di saat kamu memiliki waktu senggang!</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Esistono molti modi per leggere fumetti; uno di questi, che è diventato il più comune negli ultimi anni, è col computer. Peruse è stato creato per rendere tutto il più semplice e piacevole possibile, per farti leggere facilmente i tuoi fumetti. Si potrebbe dire che ti permette di esaminare a tuo piacimento i fumetti, ma sarebbe un modo per farla semplice - però, esamina i fumetti a tuo piacimento!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">만화책을 읽을 수 있는 방법에는 여러 가지가 있으며 컴퓨터로도 만화책을 읽을 수 있습니다. Peruse는 만화책을 쉽고 간편하게 읽을 수 있는 방법을 제공합니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Er zijn vele manieren om stripboeken te lezen en een van deze, die meer in voorbije jaren algemeen is geworden, is op een computer. Peruse is gamaakt op een manier om precies dat zo gemakkelijk en plezierig als mogelijk te maken, en eenvoudig uit de weg te gaan en u uw stripboeken te laten lezen. Men zou kunnen zeggen dat het u toestaat door uw stipboeken te dwalen als vermaak, maar dat is een rare manier om het zo te zeggen - dus, dwaal door uw stripboeken om u te vermaken!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Istnieje wiele sposobów na to, aby czytać komiksy, a tym który stał się w ostatnich czasach bardziej powszechnym, jest na komputerze. Peruse został stworzony, tak aby można było to zrobić jak najłatwiej i najprzyjemniej jak to tylko możliwe i tak aby zejść ci z drogi i pozwolić czytać komiksy.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Existem muitas formas de ler bandas desenhadas, e uma das que se tornou mais comum recentemente é num computador. O Peruse foi criado como uma forma de fazer exactamente isso da forma mais agradável possível, saindo simplesmente do caminho e deixando-o ler as suas bandas desenhadas. Pode-se dizer que lhe permite usar os seus livros de banda desenhada para o seu lazer, mas isso seria uma forma estranha de o colocar - como tal, use os seus livros de banda desenhada à sua vontade!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Obstaja veliko načinov za branje stripov. Eden teh, ki postaja zadnja leta vse pogostejši, je na računalniku. Peruse smo ustvarili, da bi to počeli čim bolj enostavno in prijetno, ter vam preprosto ponudili način branja stripov. Lahko bi rekli, da omogoča, da v prostem času berete svoje stripe, vendar bi bilo to bilo neumno - omogoča, da si v prostem času ogledujete stripe!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Det finns många sätt att läsa serietidningar, och ett av dem som har blivit allt vanligare den senaste tiden är med en dator. Peruse skapades som ett sätt att göra precis det, så enkelt och behagligt som möjligt, och att helt enkelt hålla sig undan och låta dig läsa dina serietidningar. Man skulle kunna säga att det tillåter dig att noga läsa (peruse på engelska) dina serietidningar i lugn och ro, men det skulle vara ett fånigt sätt att säga det - så läs dina serietidningar i lugn och ro!</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Çizgi roman okumanın birçok yolu var ve son yıllarda daha yaygın hale gelenlerden biri de bilgisayardadır. Peruse, bunu olabildiğince kolay ve keyifli hale getirmenin ve yalnızca aradan çekilip çizgi romanlarınızı okumanıza izin vermenin bir yolu olarak yaratıldı. Çizgi romanlarınızı boş zamanlarınızda incelemenize izin verdiği söylenebilir; ancak bu onu ifade etmenin aptalca bir yolu olurdu — bu yüzden çizgi romanlarınızı boş zamanlarınızda inceleyin!</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Читати комікси можна у декілька способів. Останнім часом усе більшої популярності набуває читання коміксів за допомогою комп'ютера. Peruse було створено для полегшення читання коміксів на комп'ютері. Програма має усунути усі можливі завади так, щоб ви могли повністю зануритися у споглядання книги і отримати максимум задоволення від неї!</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxThere are many ways to read comic books, and one of those that has become more common in recent years is on a computer. Peruse was created as a way to make exactly that as easy and pleasant as possible, and to simply get out of the way and let you read your comic books. One could say that it allows you to peruse your comic books at your leisure, but that would be a silly way of putting it - so, peruse your comic books at your leisure!xx</p>
    <p>
      One of the ways in which Peruse ensures your reading experience is as pleasant
      and effortless as possible is to allow you to simply pick up where you last left
      off. The welcome page in the application (first screenshot below) shows you your
      most recently read comics, and shows your progress through them. To pick up
      where you left off, simply tap the top left item and you will be taken right to
      the page you were reading before you had to stop.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Una de les maneres en què el Peruse us assegura que l'experiència de lectura serà agradable i sense esforç és senzillament retornar a on ho vàreu deixar. La pàgina de benvinguda de l'aplicació (la primera captura de pantalla de sota) us mostra els còmics llegits més recents, i mostra el seu progrés. Per a tornar a on ho vàreu deixar, només toqueu l'element superior de l'esquerra i anireu directe a la pàgina que estàveu llegint abans d'aturar-vos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Una de les maneres en què Peruse vos assegura que l'experiència de lectura serà agradable i sense esforç és senzillament retornar a on ho vàreu deixar. La pàgina de benvinguda de l'aplicació (la primera captura de pantalla de davall) vos mostra els còmics llegits més recents, i mostra el seu progrés. Per a tornar a on ho vàreu deixar, només toqueu l'element superior de l'esquerra i anireu directe a la pàgina que estàveu llegint abans de parar-vos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">One of the ways in which Peruse ensures your reading experience is as pleasant and effortless as possible is to allow you to simply pick up where you last left off. The welcome page in the application (first screenshot below) shows you your most recently read comics, and shows your progress through them. To pick up where you left off, simply tap the top left item and you will be taken right to the page you were reading before you had to stop.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Unu el la manieroj, per kiuj Peruse certigas, ke via legado estas kiel eble plej agrabla kaj senpene, estas permesi al vi simple repreni kie vi laste ĉesis. La bonvena paĝo en la aplikaĵo (unua ekrankopio malsupre) montras al vi viajn plej lastatempe legitajn bildstriojn, kaj montras vian progreson tra ili. Por repreni tie, kie vi ĉesis, simple frapeti la supran maldekstran eron kaj vi estos kondukata rekte al la paĝo, kiun vi legis antaŭ ol vi devis halti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Una de las maneras en las que Peruse se asegura de que su experiencia de lectura es tan placentera y sencilla como sea posible es que le permite continuar leyendo donde lo dejó la última vez. La página de bienvenida (la primera captura de pantalla, más abajo) muestra sus cómics más recientemente leídos y muestra su progreso en ellos. Para continuar leyendo donde lo dejó, simplemente pulse el elemento arriba a la izquierda y será llevado directamente a la página donde estaba leyendo cuando tuvo que parar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Üks viise, kuidasa Peruse üritab sinu lugemiselamust võimalikult nauditavaks ja pingutusevabaks muuta, on võimalus jätkata lugemist sealt, kus see viimati pooleli jäi. Rakenduse avalehekülg (esimene ekraanipilt) näitab nii viimati loetud koomikseid kui ka neis edenemist. Jätkamiseks sealt, kus lugemine pooleli jäi, klõpsa lihtsalt kirje ülemisse vasakusse nurka ning satud kohe leheküljele, mille juures viimati lugemine katki jäi.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Peruse varmistaa mahdollisimman miellyttävän ja vaivattoman lukemiskokemuksen sallimalla sinun jatkaa siitä, mihin viimeksi jäit. Sovelluksen tervetulonäkymä (ensimmäinen ruutukaappauskuva alla) näyttää viimeksi luetut sarjakuvat sekä kuinka pitkällä niissä olet. Voit jatkaa siitä mihin jäit yksinkertaisesti napauttamalla ylävasenta kohtaa, jolloin siirryt suoraan sivulle, jota viimeksi keskeyttäessäsi luit.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">L'application Peruse vous offre d'une de ces façons, une expérience de lecture est aussi agréable et sans effort que possible. Elle vous permet de se souvenir simplement de l'endroit où vous vous êtes arrêté. La page de bienvenue de l'application (la première copie d'écran ci-dessous) vous montre les bandes dessinées les plus récemment lus. Elle vous montre l'avancée de votre lecture. Pour vous vous rappelez où vous vous êtes arrêté, cliquez simplement sur l'élément en haut et à gauche. Et vous vous retrouverez juste sur la page que vous étiez entrain de lire avant de vous interrompre.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Unha das formas que ten Peruse de asegurarse de que a experiencia de lectura é todo o agradábel e cómoda posíbel é permitirlle continuar desde onde quedou a última vez. A páxina de benvida da aplicación (a primeira captura de pantalla embaixo) mostra os últimos libros de banda deseñada que leu, e mostra o seu progreso en cada un. Para continuar onde quedara, seleccione o elemento da parte superior esquerda e abrirase a páxina que estaba a ler a última vez.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Salahsatu cara di mana Peruse memastikan pengalaman pembacaanmu senyaman dan sesederhana mungkin adalah dengan memungkinkan kamu untuk mengambil dari mana kamu terakhir meninggalkannya. Halaman pembuka di aplikasi (screenshot pertama di bawah) menunjukkan komik terbaru yang kamu baca, dan menunjukkan di mana progres kamu berlangsung. Untuk mengambil di mana saat kamu meninggalkan, cukup ketuk butir kiri atas dan kamu akan dibawa langsung ke halaman yang sedang kamu baca sebelum kamu harus berhenti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Uno dei modi in cui Peruse ti garantisce che la tua esperienza di lettura sarà più piacevole e con il minimo sforzo possibile è permetterti di ricominciare in modo semplice da dove ti eri interrotto l'ultima volta. La pagina di benvenuto dell'applicazione (la prima schermata di seguito) ti mostra i fumetti più letti di recente, e ti mostra i tuoi progressi. Per ricominciare da dove ti eri interrotto, tocca semplicemente l'oggetto in alto a sinistra: verrai portato esattamente nella pagina che stavi leggendo prima di esserti fermato.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Peruse에서 만화책을 읽기 편하게 해 주는 기능 중에는 마지막에 읽었던 지점에서 다시 시작하는 기능이 있습니다. 아래 화면에 나와 있는 앱의 시작 페이지에는 최근에 읽었던 만화책과 독서 진행 상황이 표시됩니다. 마지막으로 읽었던 지점에서 다시 시작하려면 그냥 누르기만 하면 됩니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Een van de manieren waarop Peruse uw leeservaring zo plezierig en zonder inspanning als mogelijke maakt is om u verder te laten gaan waar u als laatste stopte. De welkomstpagina in de toepassing (eerste onderstaande schermafdruk) toont u uw meest recent gelezen strips en toont hoe u daarin bent gevorderd. Om verder te gaan waar u bent gestopt, tik eenvoudig op het bovenste verlaten item en u zult direct naar de pagina gaan waar u eerder bent geëindigd met lezen voordat u moest stoppen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Jednym ze sposobów w jaki Peruse zapewnia, aby czynność czytania była tak przyjemna i łatwa jak to tylko możliwe, jest wznowienie tam, gdzie przestałeś. Strona powitalna w aplikacji (pierwszy zrzut ekranu poniżej) pokazuje tobie twoje poprzednio czytane komiksy i postęp w ich czytaniu. Aby wznowić w miejscu, w którym przerwałeś, po prostu stuknij w element w górnym lewym narożniku i zostaniesz przeniesiony bezpośrednio do strony, którą czytałeś zanim przerwałeś.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Uma das formas nas quais o Peruse garante que a sua experiência de leitura se torna tão agradável e simples quanto possível é simplesmente pegar onde deixou da última vez. A página de boas-vindas na aplicação (primeira imagem em baixo) mostra-lhe as suas bandas desenhadas mais recentes, mostrando o seu progresso nelas. Para pegar onde deixou da última vez, basta tocar no item no canto superior-esquerdo para que passe logo para a página que estava a ler antes de parar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Eden izmed načinov, kako Peruse poskrbi, da je vaša bralna izkušnja prijetna in brez napora, je, da vam omogoča, da vas preprosto napoti tja, kjer ste nazadnje končali. Stran dobrodošlice v programu (prvi posnetek zaslona spodaj) prikazuje vaše zadnje brane stripe in prikazuje vaš napredek. Če želite izbrati mesto, kjer ste prenehali brati, preprosto tapnite zgornji levi element in preusmeril vas bo na stran, ki ste jo prebrali, preden ste prenehali brati.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Ett av sätten som Peruse garanterar att läsupplevelsen är så behaglig och enkel som möjligt är att låta dig enkelt fortsätta där du senast slutade. Programmets välkomstsida (första skärmbilden nedan) visar dina senast lästa serietidningar, och visar hur långt du kommit i dem. För att fortsätta där du slutade, tryck helt enkelt på objektet längst upp till vänster så kommer du direkt till sidan som du höll på att läsa innan du behövde sluta.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Peruse’un okuma deneyiminizi olabildiğince keyifli ve zahmetsiz hale getirmenin yollarından biri, en son kaldığınız yerden sürdürmenize izin vermektir. Uygulamadaki karşılama sayfası (aşağıdaki ilk ekran görüntüsü) size en son okuduğunuz çizgi romanları açar ve bunlar arasındaki ilerlemenizi gösterir. Kaldığınız yerden sürdürmek için sol üstteki ögeye dokunmanız yeterlidir; durmak zorunda kalmadan önce okumakta olduğunuz sayfaya yönlendirilirsiniz.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Однією з можливостей, яку пропонує вам Peruse для спрощення читання, є можливість продовжувати читання з місця, на якому ви востаннє зупинилися. На сторінці вітання програми (перший з наведених нижче знімків) буде показано список коміксів, які ви читали останніми, та дані щодо поступу читання. Щоб перейти до місця, де ви зупинилися, просто натисніть пункт вгорі ліворуч, і програма відкриє вам сторінку, яку ви читали останньою.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxOne of the ways in which Peruse ensures your reading experience is as pleasant and effortless as possible is to allow you to simply pick up where you last left off. The welcome page in the application (first screenshot below) shows you your most recently read comics, and shows your progress through them. To pick up where you left off, simply tap the top left item and you will be taken right to the page you were reading before you had to stop.xx</p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Característiques:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Característiques:</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Vlastnosti:</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Leistungsmerkmale:</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Features:</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Trajtoj:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Características:</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Omadused:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Ominaisuuksia:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Fonctionnalités :</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Fitur:</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Funzionalità:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">თვისებები:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">기능:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Mogelijkheden:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pa">ਫੀਚਰ:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Możliwości:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Возможности:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Funkcie:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Zmožnosti:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Funktioner:</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Özellikler:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Можливості:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxFeatures:xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">功能：</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">功能：</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Comic Book Archive (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Arxiu de llibres de còmic (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Arxiu de llibres de còmic (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Archiv knihy komiksů (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Comic-Book-Archive (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Comic Book Archive (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">Comic Book Archive (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Archivos de cómic (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Koomiksiarhiiv (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Sarjakuvakirja-arkisto (*.cbz, *.cbr, *.cb7, *.cbt, *.cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Archive de bandes dessinées (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Arquivo de libro de banda deseñada (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Arsip Buku Komik (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Archivi di fumetti (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ka">კომიქსების წიგნის არქივი (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">만화책 압축 파일(cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Archief voor stripboeken (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pa">ਕਾਮਿਕਸ ਬੁੱਕ ਅਕਾਇਵ (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Zeszyty komiksów (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Pacote de Banda Desenhada (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Komiksový archív (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Arhiv stripov (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Serietidningsarkiv (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Çizgi Roman Arşivi (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота з архівами коміксів (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxComic Book Archive (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">漫畫書封存檔 (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li>Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Format de document portable (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Format de document portable (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Portables Dokumentformat (PDF)</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">Portebla Dokumenta Formato (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Porditav dokumendivorming (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">PDF (Portable Document Format, *.pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Format de document portable (*.pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Formato portátil de documentos (PDF)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Formato di documenti portabili (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ka">გადატანადი დოკუმენტის ფორმატი(pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">PDF(Portable Document Format)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pa">ਪੋਰਟੇਬਲ ਡੌਕੂਮੈਂਟ ਫਾਰਮੈਟ (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Przenośny Format Dokumentów (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Formato de Documento Portátil (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Prenosni zapis dokumentov (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Portable Dokumentformat (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Taşınabilir Belge Biçimi (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота із портативним форматом документів (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxPortable Document Format (pdf)xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">可攜式文件格式 (pdf)</li>
      <li>ePub Books (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Llibres ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Llibres ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Knihy ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">ePub-Bücher (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">ePub Books (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">ePub-Libroj (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Libros ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">ePubi raamatud (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">ePub-kirjat (*.epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Format ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Libros ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Buku ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Libri ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ka">წიგნები ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">ePub 전자책(epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">ePub boeken (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pa">ePub ਕਿਤਾਬਾਂ (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Książki ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Livros ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Knihy ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">E-knjige ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">ePub-böcker (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">ePub Kitapları (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота з книгами ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxePub Books (epub)xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">ePub 書本 (epub)</li>
      <li>DeVice Independent files (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Fitxers independents del dispositiu (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Fitxers independents del dispositiu (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Soubory nezávislé na zařízení (DeVice Independent files - dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Geräteunabhängiges Dateiformat (DVI)</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">DeVice Independent files (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">Sendependaj dosieroj de Aparato (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Archivos DeVice Independent (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Seadmest sõltumatud failid (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Laiteriippumattomat tiedostot (DVI, *.dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Fichiers indépendants de périphériques (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Ficheiros independentes do dispositivo (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">File-file DeVice Independent (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">File indipendenti dal dispositivo (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ka">DeVice დამოკიდებელი ფაილები (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">장치 독립 파일(DeVice Independent files, DVI)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">DeVice Independent bestanden (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Pliki niezależne od urządzenia (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Ficheiros Independentes do Dispositivo (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">DeVice Independent súbory (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Datoteke, neodvisne od naprave (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">DeVice oberoende filer (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Aygıttan Bağımsız dosyalar (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота із файлами DeVice Independent (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDeVice Independent files (dvi)xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">DeVice 獨立檔案 (dvi)</li>
      <li>DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">DeJaVu-tiedostot (*.djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ka">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">DeJaVu(djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота з файлами DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDeJaVu (djvu)xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li>Compiled Help (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Ajuda compilada (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Ajuda compilada (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Kompilovaná nápověda (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Kompilierte Hilfe (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Compiled Help (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="eo">Kompilita Helpo (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Compiled Help (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Kompileeritud abi (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Käännetty ohje (*.chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Aide compilée (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Axuda compilada (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Compiled Help (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Aiuto compilato (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ka">აწყობილი დახმარების ფაილი (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">컴파일된 도움말(chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Gecompileerde help (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pa">ਕੰਪਾਇਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਮਦਦ (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Skompilowana pomoc (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Ajuda Compilada (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Kompilovaná nápoveda (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Sestavljena pomoč (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Kompilerad hjälp (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Derlenmiş Yardım (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота з файлами компільованої довідки (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxCompiled Help (chm)xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-TW">編譯過的說明文件 (chm)</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image width="1797" height="1155">https://peruse.kde.org/screenshots/peruse-welcome.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image width="1886" height="1152">https://peruse.kde.org/screenshots/peruse-reading-sidebar.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image width="1839" height="1124">https://peruse.kde.org/screenshots/peruse-book-details.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.80" date="2021-04-20" type="stable"/>
    <release version="1.2" date="2016-12-22" type="stable"/>
    <release version="1.1" date="2016-07-04" type="stable"/>
    <release version="1.0" date="2016-06-21" type="stable"/>
  </releases>
  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">360</display_length>
  </requires>
  <url type="homepage">https://peruse.kde.org/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=peruse</url>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <provides>
    <binary>peruse</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
