<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2016 Dan Leinir Turthra Jensen <admin@leinir.dk> -->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.peruse.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Peruse</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxPerusexx</name>
  <summary>Comic Book Reader</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Lector de llibres de còmic</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Lector de llibres de còmic</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Čtečka komixů</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Anzeigeprogramm für Comic-Book</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Lector de cómics</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Lector de libros de banda deseñada</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Pembaca Buku Komik</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Lettore di fumetti</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Stripboekreader</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Leitor de Bandas Desenhadas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Čítačka komiksoc</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Serietidningsläsare</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Програма для читання коміксів</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxComic Book Readerxx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      There are many ways to read comic books, and one of those that has become more
      common in recent years is on a computer. Peruse was created as a way to make
      exactly that as easy and pleasant as possible, and to simply get out of the
      way and let you read your comic books. One could say that it allows you to
      peruse your comic books at your leisure, but that would be a silly way of
      putting it - so, peruse your comic books at your leisure!
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Hi ha moltes maneres de llegir còmics, i una de les que ha esdevingut més normal en anys recents és en un ordinador. El Peruse es va crear com una manera de fer-ho exactament tant fàcil i agradable com fos possible, i per senzillament oblidar-se de la manera i permetre llegir els llibres de còmic. Es podria dir que permet llegir atentament els llibres de còmic en el temps de lleure, però això seria una manera forassenyada de dir-ho, així que llegiu atentament els llibres de còmic en el vostre temps de lleure!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Hi ha moltes maneres de llegir còmics, i una de les que ha esdevingut més normal en anys recents és en un ordinador. El Peruse es va crear com una manera de fer-ho exactament tant fàcil i agradable com fos possible, i per senzillament oblidar-se de la manera i permetre llegir els llibres de còmic. Es podria dir que permet llegir atentament els llibres de còmic en el temps de lleure, però això seria una manera forassenyada de dir-ho, així que llegiu atentament els llibres de còmic en el vostre temps de lleure!</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Hay muchas maneras de leer cómics, y una de las que se ha convertido en más común en los últimos años, es la computadora. Peruse fue creado para hacer esto de la manera más fácil y placentera posible, simplemente para no interponerse en su camino y dejarle leer cómics. Alguien podría decir que le permite leer detenidamente sus cómics a su ritmo, pero esto sería una manera un tanto tonta de ponerlo, así que, ¡Lea sus cómics a su ritmo!</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Hai moitos xeitos de ler libros de banda deseñada, e un dos máis comúns nos últimos anos é usar un computador. Peruse creouse para facer iso o máis fácil e agradábel posíbel, e para non estar no medio e deixarlle ler os seus libros de banda deseñada.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Ada banyak cara untuk membaca buku komik, dan salahsatu yang menjadi lebih umum dalam beberapa tahun terakhir adalah di komputer. Membaca dengan teliti diciptakan sebagai cara untuk membuat hal itu semudah dan semenyenangkan mungkin, dan hanya untuk keluar dari jalan dan membiarkan kamu membaca buku komikmu. Orang bisa mengatakan bahwa itu memungkinkan kamu membaca buku komikmu di waktu luangmu, tetapi itu akan menjadi cara yang konyol untuk menggambarkannya - jadi, bacalah buku komik di saat kamu memiliki waktu senggang!</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Er zijn vele manieren om stripboeken te lezen en een van deze, die meer in voorbije jaren algemeen is geworden, is op een computer. Peruse is gamaakt op een manier om precies dat zo gemakkelijk en plezierig als mogelijk te maken, en eenvoudig uit de weg te gaan en u uw stripboeken te laten lezen. Men zou kunnen zeggen dat het u toestaat door uw stipboeken te dwalen als vermaak, maar dat is een rare manier om het zo te zeggen - dus, dwaal door uw stripboeken om u te vermaken!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Existem muitas formas de ler bandas desenhadas, e uma das que se tornou mais comum recentemente é num computador. O Peruse foi criado como uma forma de fazer exactamente isso da forma mais agradável possível, saindo simplesmente do caminho e deixando-o ler as suas bandas desenhadas. Pode-se dizer que lhe permite usar os seus livros de banda desenhada para o seu lazer, mas isso seria uma forma estranha de o colocar - como tal, use os seus livros de banda desenhada à sua vontade!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Det finns många sätt att läsa serietidningar, och ett av dem som har blivit allt vanligare den senaste tiden är med en dator. Peruse skapades som ett sätt att göra precis det, så enkelt och behagligt som möjligt, och att helt enkelt hålla sig undan och låta dig läsa dina serietidningar. Man skulle kunna säga att det tillåter dig att noga läsa (peruse på engelska) dina serietidningar i lugn och ro, men det skulle vara ett fånigt sätt att säga det - så läs dina serietidningar i lugn och ro!</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Читати комікси можна у декілька способів. Останнім часом усе більшої популярності набуває читання коміксів за допомогою комп'ютера. Peruse було створено для полегшення читання коміксів на комп'ютері. Програма має усунути усі можливі завади так, щоб ви могли повністю зануритися у споглядання книги і отримати максимум задоволення від неї!</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxThere are many ways to read comic books, and one of those that has become more common in recent years is on a computer. Peruse was created as a way to make exactly that as easy and pleasant as possible, and to simply get out of the way and let you read your comic books. One could say that it allows you to peruse your comic books at your leisure, but that would be a silly way of putting it - so, peruse your comic books at your leisure!xx</p>
    <p>
      One of the ways in which Peruse ensures your reading experience is as pleasant
      and effortless as possible is to allow you to simply pick up where you last left
      off. The welcome page in the application (first screenshot below) shows you your
      most recently read comics, and shows your progress through them. To pick up
      where you left off, simply tap the top left item and you will be taken right to
      the page you were reading before you had to stop.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Una de les maneres en que el Peruse us assegura que l'experiència de lectura serà agradable i sense esforç és senzillament retornar a on ho vàreu deixar. La pàgina de benvinguda de l'aplicació (la primera captura de pantalla de sota) us mostra els còmics llegits més recents, i mostra el seu progrés. Per tornar a on ho vàreu deixar, només toqueu l'element superior de l'esquerra i anireu directe a la pàgina que estàveu llegint abans d'aturar-vos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Una de les maneres en que el Peruse vos assegura que l'experiència de lectura serà agradable i sense esforç és senzillament retornar a on ho vàreu deixar. La pàgina de benvinguda de l'aplicació (la primera captura de pantalla de sota) vos mostra els còmics llegits més recents, i mostra el seu progrés. Per tornar a on ho vàreu deixar, només toqueu l'element superior de l'esquerra i anireu directe a la pàgina que estàveu llegint abans d'aturar-vos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Una de las maneras en las que Peruse se asegura de que su experiencia de lectura es tan placentera y sencilla como sea posible es que le permite continuar leyendo donde lo dejó la última vez. La página de bienvenida (la primera captura de pantalla, más abajo) muestra sus cómics más recientemente leídos y muestra su progreso en ellos. Para continuar leyendo donde lo dejó, simplemente pulse el elemento arriba a la izquierda y será llevado directamente a la página donde estaba leyendo cuando tuvo que parar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Unha das formas que ten Peruse de asegurarse de que a experiencia de lectura é todo o agradábel e cómoda posíbel é permitirlle continuar desde onde quedou a última vez. A páxina de benvida do aplicativo (a primeira captura de pantalla embaixo) mostra os últimos libros de banda deseñada que leu, e mostra o seu progreso en cada un. Para continuar onde quedara, seleccione o elemento da parte superior esquerda e abrirase a páxina que estaba a ler a última vez.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Salahsatu cara di mana Peruse memastikan pengalaman pembacaanmu senyaman dan sesederhana mungkin adalah dengan memungkinkan kamu untuk mengambil dari mana kamu terakhir meninggalkannya. Halaman pembuka di aplikasi (screenshot pertama di bawah) menunjukkan komik terbaru yang kamu baca, dan menunjukkan di mana progres kamu berlangsung. Untuk mengambil di mana saat kamu meninggalkan, cukup ketuk item kiri atas dan kamu akan dibawa langsung ke halaman yang sedang kamu baca sebelum kamu harus berhenti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Een van de manieren waarop Peruse uw leeservaring zo plezierig en zonder inspanning als mogelijke maakt is om u verder te laten gaan waar u als laatste stopte. De welkomstpagina in de toepassing (eerste onderstaande schermafdruk) toont u uw meest recent gelezen strips en toont hoe u daarin bent gevorderd. Om verder te gaan waar u bent gestopt, tik eenvoudig op het bovenste verlaten item en u zult direct naar de pagina gaan waar u eerder bent geëindigd met lezen voordat u moest stoppen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Uma das formas nas quais o Peruse garante que a sua experiência de leitura se torna tão agradável e simples quanto possível é simplesmente pegar onde deixou da última vez. A página de boas-vindas na aplicação (primeira imagem em baixo) mostra-lhe as suas bandas desenhadas mais recentes, mostrando o seu progresso nelas. Para pegar onde deixou da última vez, basta tocar no item no canto superior-esquerdo para que passe logo para a página que estava a ler antes de parar.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Ett av sätten som Peruse garanterar att läsupplevelsen är så behaglig och enkel som möjligt är att låta dig enkelt fortsätta där du senast slutade. Programmets välkomstsida (första skärmbilden nedan) visar dina senast lästa serietidningar, och visar hur långt du kommit i dem. För att fortsätta där du slutade, tryck helt enkelt på objektet längst upp till vänster så kommer du direkt till sidan som du höll på att läsa innan du behövde sluta.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Однією з можливостей, яку пропонує вам Peruse для спрощення читання, є можливість продовжувати читання з місця, на якому ви востаннє зупинилися. На сторінці вітання програми (перший з наведених нижче знімків) буде показано список коміксів, які ви читали останніми, та дані щодо поступу читання. Щоб перейти до місця, де ви зупинилися, просто натисніть пункт вгорі ліворуч, і програма відкриє вам сторінку, яку ви читали останньою.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxOne of the ways in which Peruse ensures your reading experience is as pleasant and effortless as possible is to allow you to simply pick up where you last left off. The welcome page in the application (first screenshot below) shows you your most recently read comics, and shows your progress through them. To pick up where you left off, simply tap the top left item and you will be taken right to the page you were reading before you had to stop.xx</p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Característiques:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Característiques:</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Vlastnosti:</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Leistungsmerkmale:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Características:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Fonctionnalités :</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Fitur:</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Funzionalità:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Mogelijkheden:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Funkcie:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Funktioner:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Можливості:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxFeatures:xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">功能：</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Comic Book Archive (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Arxiu de llibres de còmic (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Arxiu de llibres de còmic (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Archiv Comic Book (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Comic-Book-Archive (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Archivos de cómic (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Arquivo de libro de banda deseñada (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Arsip Buku Komik (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Archief voor stripboeken (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Pacote de Banda Desenhada (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Komiksový archív (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Serietidningsarkiv (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота з архівами коміксів (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxComic Book Archive (cbz, cbr, cb7, cbt, cba)xx</li>
      <li>Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Format de document portable (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Format de document portable (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Portables Dokumentformat (PDF)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Formato portátil de documentos (PDF)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Formato de Documento Portátil (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Portable Document Format (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Portable Dokumentformat (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота із портативним форматом документів (pdf)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxPortable Document Format (pdf)xx</li>
      <li>ePub Books (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Llibres ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Llibres ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Knihy ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">ePub-Bücher (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Libros ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Libros ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Buku ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Libri ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">ePub boeken (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Livros ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Knihy ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">ePub-böcker (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота з книгами ePub (epub)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxePub Books (epub)xx</li>
      <li>DeVice Independent files (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Fitxers independent de dispositiu (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Fitxers independent de dispositiu (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Geräteunabhängiges Dateiformat (DVI)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Archivos DeVice Independent (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Ficheiros independentes do dispositivo (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">File-file DeVice Independent (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">DeVice Independent bestanden (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Ficheiros Independentes do Dispositivo (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">DeVice Independent súbory (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">DeVice oberoende filer (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота із файлами DeVice Independent (dvi)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDeVice Independent files (dvi)xx</li>
      <li>DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота з файлами DeJaVu (djvu)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDeJaVu (djvu)xx</li>
      <li>Compiled Help (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Ajuda compilada (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Ajuda compilada (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="cs">Kompilovaná nápověda (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Kompilierte Hilfe (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Compiled Help (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Axuda compilada (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Compiled Help (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Gecompileerde help (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Ajuda Compilada (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Kompilovaná nápoveda (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Kompilerad hjälp (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Робота з файлами компільованої довідки (chm)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxCompiled Help (chm)xx</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image width="1797" height="1155">https://peruse.kde.org/screenshots/peruse-welcome.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image width="1886" height="1152">https://peruse.kde.org/screenshots/peruse-reading-sidebar.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image width="1839" height="1124">https://peruse.kde.org/screenshots/peruse-book-details.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://peruse.kde.org/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=peruse</url>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>peruse</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
